早上好  莱纳德
Good morning,leonard.
我们开车去上班的路上
yeah.  we're gonna
要在陶瓷大库房[家居专卖店]停一下
Have to stop by pottery barn on the way to work.
我在那里买了星战床单
I bought these star wars sheets,
但躺在这上面实在是太刺激了
But they turned out to be much too stimulating
我根本不能安心睡着
To be compatible with a good night's sleep.
黑武士盯着我看  我很不爽
I don't like the way darth vader stares at me.
我不去上班了
I'm not going to work.
就算你的研究生涯这几年里毫无建树
Oh,just because your career's been stagnant
那也没必要放弃啊
For a few years,that's no reason to give up.
谢尔顿  我整晚都没睡
Sheldon,i was up all night
我在用自由电子激光束
Using the new free-electron laser
做X射线散射实验
For x-ray diffraction experiment.
是不是激光束碰巧把你视网膜烤焦了
Did the laser accidentally burn out your retinas?
没
No.
那你就能开车了  快走
Then you can drive. let's go.
我不是告诉你了么  我现在是晚上工作
Didn't I tell you I'd be working nights
你要另外想办法了
And that you'd have to make other arrangements?
是啊
You did.
所以
And?
我没办法
I didn't.
走吧
Let's go.
晚安  谢尔顿
Good night,sheldon.
那我怎么去上班啊
But how am I going to get to work?
乘公交车
Take the bus.
我再也不能乘公交车了
I can't take the bus anymore.
车上没安全带啊
They don't have seat belts,and they won't let you
而且他们不让我用橡皮绳子把自己拴在座椅上
Latch yourself to the seat with bungee cords.
你想用橡皮绳子把自己捆在座椅上
You tried to latch yourself to the seat with bungee cords?
我不是想  我已经做到了
I didn't try. I succeeded.
但不知为什么  其他乘客对此很惊慌
But for some reason,it alarmed the other passengers
他们让我滚下车
And I was asked to de-bus.
傻孩子
Oh,you're a big boy.
你会自己想出办法的
You'll figure it out.
别把我当孩子
Don't talk to me like I'm a child.
你现在立刻带我去退掉星战床单
Now,take me to return  my star wars sheets!
佩妮
Penny?
佩妮  佩妮
Penny? penny?
谢尔顿  你搞什么
Sheldon. what is it?
莱纳德睡着了
Leonard's asleep.
谢谢你的最新更新
Thanks for the update.
别  等等
No. wait.
你一定要开车送我去上班
You have to drive me to work.
我看未必
Yeah,i really don't think I do.
但我不会开车  我也不想坐公交车
But I don't drive,and I can't take the bus.
只要你不用那橡皮绳
Honey,you'll be fe as long as you don't do
坐公交肯定没问题的
That bungee cord thing,okay?
佩妮
Penny.
你不是声称我们是朋友吗
Didn't you recently stated that you and I are friends?
是的  谢尔顿  我们是朋友
Yes,sheldon. we are friends.
所以说我在这儿是引用
Then I hereby invoke what I'm given to understand
我们隐含的友谊契约书中的一个重要部分
Is an integral part of the implied covenant of friendship.
帮助
The favor.
上帝啊
Oh,dear god.
对不起  我不是故意
I'm sorry,i didn't realize
来打扰你做早晨祷告
I was interrupting your morning prayers.
你做完了我们就出发
When you're done,we'll go.
《生活大爆炸》
第二季  第05集
谢谢你送我去上班
Thank you for driving me to work.
今天是我的休息日  谢尔顿
You know this is my day off,sheldon.
太好了  看来我没有耽误你什么事
Oh,good. I'm not keeping you from anything.
你的"检查引擎"灯亮着
Your "check engine" light is on.
一般来说  这算是提醒你
Typically that's an indicator
去检查引擎
To,you know,check your engine.
没什么事  这灯亮了一个月了
It's fine. it's been on for,like,a month.
这样说来的话  那你就有更多的理由去
Well,actually,that would be all the more reason to...
检查引擎了
You know,check your engine.
谢尔顿  我的车没事
Sheldon,it's fine.
如果没事的话
If it were fine,
那这灯就不会亮了
The light wouldn't be on.
制造商装了这个灯
That's why the manufacturer installed that light,
就是为了告诉你有问题
To let you know it's not fine.
大概是这灯坏了
Maybe the light's broken.
有没有检查"检查引擎灯"的灯
Is there a "check the 'check engine light' light"?
干嘛
What?
试验表明  在开车的时候
Studies have shown that performing tasks
某些行为  诸如吃东西  打电话
Such as eating,talking on a cell phone
或者喝咖啡
Or drinking coffee while driving
会降低人的反应速度
Reduces one's reaction time
就跟喝了一盎司酒精一样
By the same factor as an ounce of alcohol.
你带酒了吗
Do you have any alcohol?
当然没有
Of course not.
可惜了
Too bad.
你要走欧几里德大道吗
You're going up euclid avenue?
莱纳德是从洛斯罗布斯大道开的
Leonard takes los robles avenu
随便他
Well,good for leonard.
欧几里德大道是直线距离  的确更近
Euclid avenue is shorter as the crow flies,
但是这里有减速坡  会极大地降低
But it has speed bumps,which appreciably increase
点到点的行驶速度
Point-to-point drive time,
所以走这条路实际上更慢
Making It the less efficient choice.
但是方向盘是在你手里
But you have the conn.
当然了  如果你在过减速坡的时候
Of course,if you're not going to slow down
不减速的话
For the speed bumps,
那我就收回之前的意见
I withdraw my previous objection.
我有一个有趣的问题
Here's a fun question.
你知道最常见的街道名字是什么吗
Do you know what the most common street name is?
不知道
No.
是个脑筋急转弯
The answer's tricky.
二街
It's second street.
你可能认为该是"一街"
You see,you'd think it would be first street,
但大多数地方
But in most towns,first street eventually
一街都用一些别的名字代替
Gets renamed to something else.
比如  主路
You know,like main street,
大街
Broad street.
密歇根大道[为1893年哥伦比亚博览会修建]
Michigan avenue.
莱纳德和我在路上经常找一些
See,leonard and I   often use our commute time
像这样的脑筋急转弯来锻炼大脑
To exercise our minds  with brain-teasers like that.
我们也玩游戏
We also play games.
想玩么
Would you like to play one?
不
No.
来吧  可好玩了
Oh,come on. it's fun.
噢  又一个减速坡
Ooh! another bump.
这样吧  我说一个元素名称
Okay. I'll say an element,and,and you say an element
你也说一个
Whose name starts with the last letter
以我说的元素的尾字母开头
Of the one I said,okay?
从我开始
I'll start.
氦[Helium]
Helium.
你可以说汞[Mercury]
Now,you could say "mercury."
你给我一个"y"
That would give me a "y."
非常聪明  这个可不容易
Ooh. very clever.   that's a tough one.
镱[ytterbium]  让你又回到了"m"
So I go with "ytterbium," which gets you back to "m."
你可以说钼[molybdenum]  我说镁[magnesium]
So you go "molybdenum," and I say "magnesium."
你可以说锰[manganese]  我说铕[europium]
You say "manganese." I say "europium,"
现在你只剩下钔了[mendelevium]
And,then,you're left with "mendelevium,"
然后就没有以"m"开头的了
And... there are   no more m's
因为我相信[meitnerium]
Because I believe that meitnerium
应该被叫做ekairidium[一种过渡元素]
Should still be called ekairidium.
恭喜你  你赢了
So,congratulations. you win.
想再来一局么
Do you wanna go again?
我们就不能安静一会儿么
Why don't we just have a little quiet time now?
没问题
All right.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我觉得你对于引擎检查提示灯的
I'm finding your reckless nonchalance
冷漠鲁莽非常糟糕
Regarding the check-engine light to be very troubling.
下车
Get out.
我不得不说
Well,i ve to tell you
关于内燃机引擎工作的原理
That while I do have a theoretical understanding
我是有一定了解的
Of the workings of an internal combustion engine,
不过我不确定能不能看出毛病在哪
I'm not sure I'm capable  of performing diagnostics.
我说了  下车
I said,"get out."
好吧  我就去试试好了
Okay. I'll give it a shot.
莱纳德  你在这儿呢
Oh,leonard. there you are.
我准备好回家了
I'm ready to go home.
我才刚到这
T1  I just got here.
真及时
Good. perfect timing.
谢尔顿
Sheldon,
我告诉过你啦  我只有晚上
Told you,i only have access
使用自由电子激光器的权限
To the free-electron laser at night.
这几个星期我都不能开车送你
I can't drive you for the next few weeks.
不对  你是说过你不能开车送我上班
No,you said you couldn't drive me to work.
但现在说的是下班
this is from work.
霍华德帮我说句话啊
Howard,help me out here.
不  我要站在他那边  这样有意思多了
No,just for the fun of it,i'm gonna take his side.
那么
Now,
你觉得我该怎么回家
How do you propose I get home?
你是怎么来的呢
How did you get here in the first place?
佩妮
Penny.
但我觉得这个选项已经没可能了
But I sense that's no longer an option.
反正我要用激光实验室
Look,i need to get edto the laser lab.
你只能找别人
You're just gonna have
送你回家了
To find someone else to take you home.
该死  我站错队了
Ah,damn,i picked the wrong side.
老天  不要走欧几里德大道吧
Oh,god,not euclid avenue!
到底为什么霍华德把你
Why did howard leave you
扔在半道上
In the middle of the road anyway?
我们观点不统一
We had a difference of opinion.
什么观点
Over what?
关于他是不是要害死我
Whether or not he was trying to kill me.
事实可鉴  我坚持他就是
For the record,i maintain he was.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
带你回家啊
I'm taking you home.
但我先不回家的
Oh,but I'm not going home.
今天礼拜三
It's wednesday.
礼拜三是漫画书购买日
Wednesday's new comic book day.
我们必须先去动漫书店
We have to go to the comic book store.
之后  我们在种汤小吃店停下
And then,we have to stop
因为今天还是奶油土豆汤日
At soup plantation; it's creamy tomato soup day.
最后是雷都夏克电器行
And radio shack.
今天有个3A电池的折扣
There's a sale on triple-a batteries.
对了还有  我们还得去下陶瓷大库房
Plus,we have to go to pottery barn
我要把我的星战床单退了
And return my star wars sheets.
我有个更好的主意
I have a better idea.
你想先去陶瓷大库房啊
You want to go to pottery barn first?
你能开车送我去陶瓷大库房吗
Can you drive me to pottery barn?
如果我把夜明灯关了
Maybe if I turn off the night-light,
这床单还能用
I can keep the sheets.
早上好
Good morning.
谢尔顿  坐下
Sheldon,sit down.
她坐了我的位置
She's in my spot.
别那么看着我
Don't look at me like that.
谁都知道那是我的位置
Everybody knows that my spot.
谢尔顿  你知道我们都很关心你
Sheldon,you know  that we care about you.
就是因为我们关心你
And it's because we care about you
才不得不说
That we've decided we have to speak up.
亲爱的  你让你身边的人都头疼了
You're hurting the people around you,sweetie.
我们帮你做了个预约
So we made you an appointment,
想让你接受
And we want you to keep it.
机动车辆管理局新司机手册
Department of motor vehicles new driver handbook?
但我没有什么需要查的
But I don't have a problem.
谢尔顿  你得学会开车
Sheldon,you need to learn how to drive.
不能再这样疯下去了
This madness has to stop.
佩妮带你去车管局
Penny's taking you to the dmv.
我去睡觉
I'm going to bed.
为什么是佩妮
Why penny?
因为石头赢过剪子[石头剪子布游戏]
Because rock breaks scissors.
晚安
Good night.
好了  走吧  谢尔顿
All right,come on,sheldon.
等下
Hold on.
我有个条件
I have one condition.
什么
What?
得去趟陶瓷大库房
We have to stop at pottery barn.
好的
Okay.
还有雷都夏克电器行
And radio shack.
行
Fine.
还有动漫书店
And the comic book store.
可以
All right!
我想去动漫书店
Ooh,i want to go to the comic book store.
我也喜欢漫画书
I like comic books.
我只是不明白我为什么需要驾驶执照
I just don't see why I need a driver's license.
阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦从没有过驾驶执照
Albert einstein never had a driver's license.
是啊  但阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦从不在每小时
Yeah,but albert einstein didn't make me wet myself
40英里时让我惊出一身冷汗
At 40 miles an hour.
我也从不会把阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦疯狂地赶下车
Yeah,and I never wanted to kick albert einstein in the nuts.
我想问问  你为什么不和别人一样
You know,i gotta ask,why didn't you just
在16岁的时候考取驾照
Get a license at 16 like everybody else?
我在忙别的事
I was otherwise engaged.
做什么
Doing what?
验证超对称理论中n=4的情况下
Examining perturbative amplitudes
的扰动振幅
In n=4 supersymmetric theories
再用现代扭量理论重新验证
Leading to a re-examination of the ultraviolet properties
n=8时回路超引力场的紫外特性
Of multi-loop n=8 supergravity using modern twistor theory.
那你17岁的时候呢
Well,how 'bout when you were 17?
带这个去测试区
Take this to the testing area,
在上面写上名字  下面签字
Put your name at the top,sign the bottom,
回答完问题交回来  下一个
Answer the questions,bring it back. next
申请
Application?
我实际上更多是理论家
I'm actually more of a theorist.
是说你手里的申请表
The application in your hand.
给她
Give it to her.
带这个去测试区
Take this to the testing area,
在上面写上名字  下面签字
Put your name at the top,sign the bottom,
回答完问题交回来  下一个
Answer the questions,bring it back. next!
抱歉  对这些问题我有些疑问
Excuse me,but I have some concerns about these questions.
看看那的标志牌
Look at that sign up there.
怎么了
Yes?
上面写了"我在乎"吗
Does it say "i give a damn"?
没
No.
那是因为我不在乎
That's because I don't.
就看一眼
Just look.
第一个问题就说不通
See,this first question makes no sense.
"当开车时与前车
"how many car lengths
的车距应该保持几个车身"
Should you leave in front of you when driving?"
没有可能能回答这个问题
There's no possible way to answer that.
"车身长"不是个标准化的度量单位
A "car length" is not a standardized unit of measure.
看看标志牌
Look at the sign.
谢尔顿  答案是"C"  就写"C"
Sheldon,it's "c." just put down "c."
我不需要你的帮忙  佩妮
I don't need yourelp,penny.
听那个小姑娘的  宝贝
Listen to that little girl,honey.
写上"C"  下一个
Put "c." next!
别  等下  等等
No,wait! no,hang on.
看看下一个问题
Look at this next question.
谢尔顿  你为何要和车管局争执
Sheldon,why are you arguing with the dmv?
否则他们怎么进步
How else are they going to learn?
听着
Look...
"什么时候路面最湿滑"
"when are roadways most slippery?"
有三个答案
Now,okay,there are three answers,
没一个是正确的
None of which are correct.
正确的答案是"当[路面]被覆盖上
The correct answer is "when covered by
一层液体足以
"a film of liquid sufficient to reduce
把轮胎和道路之间的静态摩擦系数
"the coefficient of static friction
减少到理论上的零值
"between the tire and the road to essentially zero,
又不产生新的摩擦源"
But not so deep as to introduce a new source of friction."
这是你的学习证明  走开
Here's your learner's permit. go away.
但我还没说完
But I'm not done.
我还有更多的
I have many additial concerns
关于这些问题的质疑
About these questions.
别逼我翻过这柜台
Don't make me climb over this counter.
来吧  我们走  来吧
Come on. let's go. come on.
下一个
Next!
一流
Aced it.
好了  弄好了
Okay,that's it.
开始启动吧
Let's boot it up.
启动
Booting.
这是最先进的模拟器
This is a state-of-the-art simulator.
我从一个朋友为军队
I adapted it from something
设计的东西上改装而来的
A friend of mine designed for the army.
所以我才在费鲁杰的市区里
Is that why I appear to be in downtown fallujah
跟在一辆装甲悍马的轮子后
Behind the wheel of an up-armored humvee?
我还没有配置呢
I haven't configured it yet.
看看
Let's see...
布拉德利坦克
Bradley tank...
运输卡车  蝙蝠车
Transport truck...  batmobile...
不行
Ooh! no.
就这个  2006款红色福特金牛座
Here we go. red 2006 ford taurus
驰骋在帕萨迪纳市的街道上
On the streets of pasadena.
怎么了
What?
据统计  红色车让警察叫停的次数
Statistically,red cars are stopped by police
比其它颜色的车多得多
Far more often than any other color.
我可不想跟条子发生口角
I don't want any hassles with the fuzz.
好吧  你想要什么颜色
Fine,what color do you want?
你知道天行者卢克那把淡蓝色的激光剑吗
You know the pale blue of luke skywalker's lightsaber?
当然不是后来的那个数码修复版里那种
Before it was digitally remastered?
就是黑色了
Black,it is.
好的  现在你首先要做的是
Okay,now,what you want to do first
打开点火开关
Is turn on the ignition
换到前进档
And shift into drive.
我还没系安全带呢
I haven't fastened my seat belt yet.
好吧  系上你的安全带
Okay,fasten your seat belt.
可以了
Click
这有安全气囊吗
Now,are there air bags?
你不需要安全气囊
You don't need air bags.
要是哪个模拟货车和我追尾了  怎么办
What if a simulated van  rear-ends me?
那我就用枕头给你脸一下
I'll hit you in the face with a pillow.
好的  换到前进档
Okay,now shift into drive.
慢慢开进车道
Pull out slowly into traffic.
小心  看着行人
Watch out,watch,watch out for the pedestrians!
天呢
Oh,god.
等等  慢点
Wait-- slow--
刹车  刹车
Hit the brakes! the brakes!
谢了
Thank you.
对不起
Sorry.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我的错
My bad.
新手上路
Student driver.
你怎么
How did you manage
开到幽谷拱廊商场[洛城顶级六大室内商场之一]的二层楼上了
To get on the second floor of the glendale galleria?
我不知道
I don't know.
我原来在帕萨迪纳市的高速公路  出口处没出去
I was on the pasadena freeway. I missed my exit,
冲出了天桥  之后就这样了
Flew off the overpass,and one thing led to another.
也许你该休息一下  明天再练
Maybe you want to give it a rest and try again tomorrow.
不用了  我不练了
No. I quit.
宠物商店
Aw,the pet store.
帮我谢谢沃罗威茨的软件
Remind me to compliment wolowitz on the software.
里面内容非常详尽
It's amazingly detailed.
那你就这样放弃了吗
Th  so wait,you're just gonna give up?
不是  我没放弃
No,i'm not giving up.
我从不放弃
I never give up.
那你在干嘛
So,what is it you're doing?
我就是
I'm...
情况非常的好
Transcending the situation.
很明显  我已经进化到不需要开车了
I'm clearly too evolved for driving.
这话什么意思
What does that mean?
莱纳德  你有没有想过  平均来说  为什么我的小趾
Leonard,have you ever wondered why my little toes
和侧门牙明显比像我这种身材的人
And lateral incisors are significantly smaller
的小趾和侧门牙要小
Than the average for someone of my size?
你的事  我有很多都很好奇  谢尔顿
I wonder a lot of things about you,sheldon.
不过没有这件
But not-not that.
这表明
Well,those are indicators
在进化系谱中  我比一般人
That I'm farther along the evolutionary scale
进化得更为充分
Than the average human.
-真有你的  -别走  别走
- No kidding. - well,no,no.
我这么说  并不意味着
I'm not gonna go so far as to say
我代表人类进化的新的高度
That I represent a distinct new stage in humankind--
新贵[出身低微而奋斗成功的人]  如果这是你想说的
You know,a homo novus,if you will.
不行  这得由人类学家决定
No,that's for anthropologists to decide.
但我确信
But I am convinced
我之所以不能掌握开车这种小技巧
That the rson I cannot master the plebeian task of driving
是因为我根本不想学
Is because I'm not meant to.
你想  你想的
Yes,you are.
你想去学车的
You're meant to learn how to drive.
求你了  学开车吧
Please learn how to drive!
不行  不行
No,no.
莱纳德  我是要去干大事业的
Leonard,i'm meant for greater things,
比如解开宇宙之谜
Like unraveling the mysteries of the universe,
而不是决定什么时候
Not determining when it's safe
在乡村公路上超过停在路边的校车是安全的
To pass a stopped school bus on a country road.
就没安全的时候
It's never safe.
我现在知道了
Yeah,well,i know that now.
好吧
Fine.
就算你说的全对
Assuming that everything you say is true,
那个生物学上的超级新贵
How does the biologically superior homo novus
明早怎么去上班
Get to work tomorrow morning?
新贵也不知道
Homo novus doesn't know.
坚持住
Well,hang in there.
也许你还能进化出翅膀之类的东西
Maybe you'll evolve into something with wings.
早安  先生们
Good morning,gentlemen.
早安
Hey. good morning.
这是不是什么新的星期五便装日
Is there some new kind of casual friday
而我不知道
I don't know about?
不是  他在这安家了
No,he lives here now.
真的吗  为啥
Really? why?
因为他不乘公交  而且进化得连车都开不了了
Since he won't take the bus and he's too evolved to drive,
所以决定  在我完成我的实验前
He decided it would be easier to just sleep in his office
在他办公室睡觉  在放射室洗澡
And shower in the radiation lab
可能更好
Until I'm finished with my experiment.
不过你一周前不就完成了吗
But you finished your experiment a week ago.
没错
Yep
天呢
Ay,dios mio.
又来了
Tra vez?
肯定是老鼠
Deben ser rata
老鼠不会烤面包
Las ratas no hacen pan tostado
还把面包皮切开
Y le cortan las orillas.
妈呀
Ay,dios mio!
就当什么都没看见
You saw nothing!